<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Adam Kaewell's Blog</title>
 <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2014-11-15T17:19:40-05:00</updated>
 <id>http://a2k11.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Adam</name>
   <email>adam.kaewell@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>It's Always Sunny in ... the Request, Response Cycle</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/11/15/requestresponse/"/>
   <updated>2014-11-15T00:00:00-05:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/11/15/requestresponse</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Rails Applications and the Web Server&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an internet browser, the user can interact with your application.  My job is to build
this application.  It is  difficult to become a master of developing rails
applications if I don&#39;t understand what is happening behind the scenes.  The web
server is a central part of the operation.  The request, response cycle
describes the sequence of events through which the server handles and processes
to and from a user&#39;s browser.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Frank, Dee, Mac, Dennis, and Charlie could create a rails application but it
would be horrible.  Everything would go wrong and nothing would work.  It is one
of my favorite shows and I laugh every time I watch an episode.  So we can refer
to the user as Charlie since the others would vote him out due to creative
differences.&lt;/em&gt;  Charlie interacts with the browser which shows your web
application.  Then Charlie clicks a button and that makes a request to the
server.  This request hits the web server where it first sees Rack.  Rack wraps
HTTP requests into a single method call to interface with Ruby web applications.
It&#39;s a very useful API especially if your creating a Rails application.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;At this point you would probably think Dennis would announce himself as the
manager.  It normally would be but Dennis is too obsessed with writing the about
page to be just about himself.&lt;/em&gt;  The request now sees the Rails application.
The routes, &lt;em&gt;location in the application: config/routes.rb&lt;/em&gt;, are used to figure
out where the application needs to go.  It matches the request with the
specified controller and controller action to perform.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The controller can be seen as the director of the rails application.  It
organizes the actions and defines them based on coding by the developer.  &lt;em&gt;Frank
would in charge of the controller and would make Dee in charge of the Model.&lt;/em&gt;  The
controller calls out to the model if it needs to access the business logic.
Databases are what models use to organize the information for an application.
Postgresql is a database which uses SQL to access, update, delete, and create
data objects.  The controller also renders views at the end of the interaction
between the controller and model.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Mac would want a huge part in the fame and success of this whole process.  In
this scenario he would be the view after all the actions have been processed.&lt;/em&gt;
The views are what the user sees and the controller specifies a view after it
gathers all the information and conducts the actions which we define.    The
view could have some JavaScript, CSS, and ruby code inside each HTML document
which is why we name our files accordingly (mac.html.erb, charlie.html.css,
frank.html.js, etc.).  The response is now sent back to the web server and then
to the browser where the user can view the newly rendered page.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Finding the jobs you love</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/29/Finding-Jobs-You-Love/"/>
   <updated>2014-10-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/29/Finding-Jobs-You-Love</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Elliott Bell &amp;amp; Erin Greenawald From: &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themuse.com&quot;&gt;The Muse&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Presentation @ &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.wework.com&quot;&gt;WeWork&lt;/a&gt; on October 28, 2014, 6:00-7:00PM&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What do you want to do with your life?  It&#39;s a question we all ask ourselves.
It&#39;s not an easy one to answer as we go through challenges in our career paths.
We make choices and we don&#39;t know what they&#39;ll mean down the road.  When it is
time to search for jobs our path doesn&#39;t become easier.  We keep asking
questions thinking about our skills, potential, and value to help a
company.  Do I have enough experience?  Do I stand out?  Can I provide something for
this company?  Elliott Bell and Erin Greenawald from &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.themuse.com&quot;&gt;The Muse&lt;/a&gt;
delivered an eye opening presentation about finding the jobs you love.  As we
enter the gauntlet of interviews and job searching,
&lt;strong&gt;The Muse&lt;/strong&gt; helps us with the tools we need to succeed and to find jobs which
inspire us.  Elliott explained how a company is neither good or bad, but right or
wrong for a person.  In order to accomplish your goal of acquiring that slice of paradise ( .. a
job .. ), &lt;strong&gt;The Muse&lt;/strong&gt; can offer exactly what you need.  Getting advice and gaining
knowledge from this fascinating website are a few of its many enticing features.  Erin and Elliott
presented four steps on how to not be basic when you job search:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Find the right people to work with.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People always think they want to work for Google because it&#39;s the popular,
&#39;sexy&#39; company.  This is not going to lead you to a career that makes you happy.
A company&#39;s culture defines their values and personality.  Finding the people
you fit in with and who can also make you happy are a priority in job hunting.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Talk to people at your favorite companies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learning how to have an informational interview is a great way to subtly sell
yourself.  The ability to go out, meet people, and talk to them is a huge
advantage.  Elliott described this as being your best friend.  Another key
psychological trigger is asking for help because people like to help if they
can.  Complimenting can lead to increased confidence which may inspire your
&lt;em&gt;mentor&lt;/em&gt; to help more.  If you start having a conversation then the
other person will begin to ask questions.  Don&#39;t ask if they are hiring. Make
the conversation about them because people love talking about themselves.
Creating a connection is very important.  There&#39;s nothing wrong with
specifically reaching out and being persistent unless they tell you no.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Get your application to the point.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The K.I.S.S. method (Keep It Simple, Stupid) defines how you want to keep your
application and resume to the point.  You want to have some creative, fun cover
letter to separate yourself from other applicants.  This also lets the company
know you researched and want to be a part of their culture.  And above all else,
make no spelling errors!  Always stay professional but convey how you understand
the company culture.  Explain why you love the company and why you would be a
great fit.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nail the interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Nail the little things.  It is important to stay genuine and honest while
telling your story.  But tell a great story!  It&#39;s your time to shine.  Note any
existing projects you have worked on and suggest how that experience could help
the company.  Know your value because you deserve it.  Researching a company or
other facts is acceptable and encouraged because you now have the ability to
back up your words.  Nothing is ever off the table.  The company wants to be
happy with their hire and they want their new employee to be happy too.  You
have more power than you realize.  Finally, don&#39;t ask lame questions.  Elliott
and Erin gave us some great examples of questions we should ask:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Could I sit with customer service for a day to better understand the production?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What would you like to see from me in the first 30, 60, 90 days that would make you think you made the right choice?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can you show me an example of a project you recently completed that you&#39;re really proud of?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In closing, &lt;strong&gt;The Muse&lt;/strong&gt; is a great way to hit the ground running when searching for
jobs.  They offer a lot of useful information to help market yourself and build
your skills for interviews.  I just joined today and I look forward to absorbing
all its power.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Having the Potential to be a Rockstar</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/23/Rock-Star-Potential/"/>
   <updated>2014-10-23T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/23/Rock-Star-Potential</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Rockstar Potential Interview - with Brandon Atkinson&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On Tuesday October 21, 2014, I attended a presentation which I would
describe as incredibly wise and thought provoking.  &lt;a href=&quot;http://blog.appnexus.com/author/batkinson/&quot;&gt;Brandon
Atkinson&lt;/a&gt; from
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.appnexus.com/globalservices/&quot;&gt;Global Services AppNexus&lt;/a&gt; delivered
an amazing talk titled  &lt;strong&gt;Rock Star Potential Interview Training.
&lt;/strong&gt;  I was curious but  wondered if this event would be worth my time.
I&#39;m not an interviewer and I&#39;m going to be the &lt;em&gt;victim&lt;/em&gt; of being interviewed in
the next few months.  I have the difficult challenge of keeping my head held
high while I persevere through interviews.  I was very close to going back to
my &lt;a href=&quot;https://krash.io&quot;&gt;Krash&lt;/a&gt; pad and working on my portfolio.  But I&#39;m glad I
attended Brandon&#39;s presentation and here is why.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;
Brandon Atkinson shared his experiences and knowledge about 
interviewing throughout the entire night.  He explained to us how he 
enjoyed taking nothing but potential and turning it into something powerful.
To hear a person who has hired well over a thousand people to say such
a statement is incredible. During his presentation, I listened closely to someone who wanted to hire people for the right reasons.  Brandon loves building.  
His hiring process seems intense but it makes sense to me.  He seeks to
find the greatest qualities in people which he describes as analytical 
horsepower and Rock Star Potential.  It doesn&#39;t matter what role you are 
applying for because these two qualities will take you farther than you can
imagine.  Brandon is this type of person who can imagine that place and create a
stepping stone for your career.  He will eventually ask each candidate about 
their specific technical skills and values but that comes later in his process.
They are important but not as much as this concept of potential.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
Brandon explained to us how interviewers are the guardians of alchemy.  They
are in charge of mixing together the right employees to create something
magical.  Bringing together the right employees with high potential seems
like an easy agenda item to accomplish in a business. I would have told you
before Brandon&#39;s speech that I thought hiring was easy too.  But the more I
listened, the more I started to understand how difficult it can be for the
interviewer.  I still believe interviewing for a company is just as
difficult.  Yet, I never had an interviewer ask me the types of questions
Brandon wanted to ask.  He explained how skills can be learned but intrinsic
motivation was difficult to change.  Brandon has learned how to ask the right
questions that make him understand who you are.  I would describe him as a 
human lie detector but it&#39;s more than just finding the truth.  He is just 
trying to discover genuine, authentic, and passionate people.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
One of the best example questions I heard from the night was &quot;Can you tell me 
about a time when your emotions got the best of you?&quot;  When Brandon feels the 
answer was too premeditated and too rehearsed, he asks for another example 
in order to catch you in an awkward, uncomfortable place.  There is a 
reason for all his methods and it has to deal with understanding people.  
Brandon wants to know your DNA and the force which drives your motivation.  He 
wants to know if we can learn from our mistakes, are passionate about learning,
and if we have deep commitments which we strive to finish.  Brandon explained 
how some of these people you never would have hired on paper which is mind
blowing to hear.  I was definitely inspired to hear his energy, commitment, and
belief of his concept of Rock Star Potential.
&lt;/p&gt;


&lt;p&gt;
Now I have been talking about &lt;strong&gt;Rock Star Potential&lt;/strong&gt; throughout my
blog for a reason.  If I had to sum it up in a few words, I&#39;d like to think of 
it as our internal drive to overcome adversity, to never give up, to aim high, 
and to not be afraid to take on challenges.  It is the type of person who wants
to constantly learn.  Brandon&#39;s last lesson was his approach for getting to 
know someone you are interviewing called &lt;strong&gt;Squeeze the Tomato.&lt;/strong&gt;
He wants to get underneath the surface of people so he writes down notes during
the whole process.  Odd word choice, apparent rises in anxiety levels, or just 
an unclear comment are few of the many examples.  But when he finds a soft spot on that tomato he sticks his finger in it!  I have to admit that makes me 
nervous for the next time I&#39;m being interviewed.  I asked Brandon for some 
advice for people about to be interviewed at the end of his speech.  He replied
with being prepared, researching the company you are applying to, being
authentic, and to ask for the transparency technique at the end so you can have
a chance to reinforce who you are as a potential employee.  I enjoyed attending
this event.  Even though I&#39;m not an interviewer, I learned they have a 
challenging job as well.  This will definitely help me become more prepared and
relaxed during my interviewing process.
&lt;/p&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>The Power of Vim</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/21/the-power-of-vim/"/>
   <updated>2014-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/21/the-power-of-vim</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Vim and Tmux Commands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vim is Vi Improved.  It is a text editor that is based off of vi which was a
text editor for unix based systems.  It is a free open source software which was
designed for use from a command line interface and a stand only application.  It
was first released in 1991 and has been updated 23 additional times.  For the
past 4 1/2 weeks I&#39;ve been trying to become an efficient and productive vim
user.  It is difficult to not enter &quot;INSERT&quot; mode and correct all your mistakes
by using the up and down arrows.  You have to be patient with vim in order to
learn its power and it is very powerful.  Here is a list of the common commands
I use with vim as of right now and I hope to keep adding to this arsenal over
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
VIM COMMANDS

vim (filename)         --&gt;  open filename for edits
(space) + n + t        --&gt;  new vim tab
(space) + p + (tab)    --&gt;  view next tab
(space) + n + (tab)    --&gt;  view previous tab
:!                     --&gt;  mkdir
:e                     --&gt;  newfile / mkdir
(ctrl) + p             --&gt;  search for file
:%s/oldthing/newthing  --&gt;  replace
gg                     --&gt;  go to top
(shift) + g            --&gt;  go to bottom
ciw                    --&gt;  change inside of word
.                      --&gt;  repeat change
==                     --&gt;  align line correctly
= + (shift) + g        --&gt;  align everything below
(shift) + j            --&gt;  smash two lines together
(shift) + a            --&gt;  go to end of line
e                      --&gt;  go to the end of next word
w                      --&gt;  go to the beginning of next word
:sort                  --&gt;  sort the contents
:vs                    --&gt;  split the vim window

TMUX COMMANDS

tmux -2                    --&gt;  start tmux with darker color
(ctrl + a) + (shift + 5)   --&gt;  create two terminal windows vertical
(ctrl + a) + (shift + &#39;)   --&gt;  create two terminal windows horizontal 

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I hope to add to this ever growing knowledge of commands.  It is
easier to learn by practicing editing files without ever touching your mouse.  I
like to think of it as a style of the experts which is my goal to become.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Class Relationships</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/13/has-many-belongs-to/"/>
   <updated>2014-10-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/13/has-many-belongs-to</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Has Many and Belongs To&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a relationship we can define between classes in ruby which makes it
very easy to communicate between objects in rails.  If we decide to have an
application which has a Gallery model and an Image model ( &lt;em&gt;Note classes are
singular, controllers are plural&lt;/em&gt; ), we can relate the two simply by using the
code below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
class Gallery &lt; ActiveRecord::Base
  has_many :images
end

class Image &lt; ActiverRecord::Base
  belongs_to :gallery
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Pluralizing classes is important when using these connections with another
model.  It also helps to draw an ERD (Entity Relationship Diagram) to help
decide whether you need these connections.  It makes it easier to see a solution to a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I Shook Sinatra.rb's Hand</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/03/fall-into-october/"/>
   <updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/03/fall-into-october</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Week 2 Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have made it through another week.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sinatrarb.com/&quot;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt; is a DSL, domain specific
language, for creating web applications in Ruby.  It uses routes which are HTTP
methods paired with a URL matching pattern.  Each route has a block and I have
created many routes throughout the week.  It&#39;s very interesting and fun to build an
application and be able to view your work on a local server.  I find it
rewarding to finish a project in class at the end of the day.  It makes me focus
more during class and it helps me greatly later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I should log, about this blog, go for a jog, escape the fog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really, really, really, hope to figure out this blog setup and I might start
building it from scratch.  I can&#39;t figure out how to link pages to the older and
newer tags at the bottom of the page and it&#39;s frustrating.  I also recently
joined a gym so I can start jogging and work my way up to running again.  I miss
doing cardio and I think it would relieve a lot of stress.  It definitely has
been a tough week but I figure if I made it this far I can go farther for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SQL and Final Project Status</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/09/29/sql-capstonepost/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/09/29/sql-capstonepost</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;SQL and Final Project Status 9/29/14&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have a case of the Mondays.&lt;/em&gt;  I&#39;m not feeling too well, and I believe I
caught something from NYC&#39;s various subway systems.  It also means I will be
trying to get more rest for the next couple days.  I just learned some basic
Query language code which is not too complicated.  The biggest task will be to
use SQL effectively and without trouble later on.  I have a little bit of work
to do with my final project and I&#39;m not too sure I will be able to follow
through with my proposal.  It is hard to plan this far ahead considering we are
only through week 1.  Hopefully I will be able to figure out more within the
next few days.  Here are some SQL functions I have learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SELECT * FROM (table) WHERE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ORDER BY&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LIKE and ILIKE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR, AND&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IS NULL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;...FROM (table) JOIN (another table) ON (primary = foreign keys)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GROUP BY (label)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;INSERT INTO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UPDATE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DELETE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Adam's Thoughts</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/09/26/introduction-adam/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/09/26/introduction-adam</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dedicated to help and understanding.&lt;/em&gt;  The idea of this blog is to help me
understand the concepts I learn during the week.  Hopefully I will be able to
produce posts which provide help to others who have similar problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Providing Information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My webpage is located &lt;a href=&quot;http://a2k11.github.io&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  I will also be working on
this site as time goes on.  It will get better over time, I guarantee it!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First Post</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/09/26/firstpost/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/09/26/firstpost</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;First Post 9/26/14&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&#39;m a part of this now.&lt;/em&gt;  My first week at the Ruby on Rails
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thisismetis.com&quot;&gt;Metis&lt;/a&gt; has been very cool so far.  I have met a lot
of new friends and have learned a lot about the programming language Ruby.  Here
is a list of what specifically I&#39;m working on with Ruby:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passing Blocks to Methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;def method(variable, &amp;amp;block)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;block.call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yield&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Symbols --&gt; :symbol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vim commands and becoming better at using it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My typing skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the methods .times, .each, and .map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrays and Hashes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Other Thoughts / Reflection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it has been a week now and I&#39;m a little tired.  I definitely feel great about
the progress I&#39;ve made since Monday but I don&#39;t want to become content with just
being ok.  I&#39;m literally counting the nights until I move into the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://krash.io/&quot;&gt;Krash&lt;/a&gt; place I reserved through December.  Being only two
blocks away from class will be awesome and I will probably sleep better at
night.  I also will get to cook my meals again which is something I miss doing
since it helps me eat healthy foods.  My passion project at the end of this
course is still in the works.  I submitted my outline and I hope to have
feedback sooner than later.  I hope I get a chance to view some of the sites
while I&#39;m here in New York this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
