<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

 <title>Adam Kaewell's Blog</title>
 <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
 <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/"/>
 <updated>2014-10-21T23:38:18-04:00</updated>
 <id>http://a2k11.github.io</id>
 <author>
   <name>Adam</name>
   <email>adam.kaewell@gmail.com</email>
 </author>

 
 <entry>
   <title>The Power of Vim</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/21/the-power-of-vim/"/>
   <updated>2014-10-21T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/21/the-power-of-vim</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Vim and Tmux Commands&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Vim is Vi Improved.  It is a text editor that is based off of vi which was a
text editor for unix based systems.  It is a free open source software which was
designed for use from a command line interface and a stand only application.  It
was first released in 1991 and has been updated 23 additional times.  For the
past 4 1/2 weeks I&#39;ve been trying to become an efficient and productive vim
user.  It is difficult to not enter &quot;INSERT&quot; mode and correct all your mistakes
by using the up and down arrows.  You have to be patient with vim in order to
learn its power and it is very powerful.  Here is a list of the common commands
I use with vim as of right now and I hope to keep adding to this arsenal over
time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
VIM COMMANDS

vim (filename)         --&gt;  open filename for edits
(space) + n + t        --&gt;  new vim tab
(space) + p + (tab)    --&gt;  view next tab
(space) + n + (tab)    --&gt;  view previous tab
:!                     --&gt;  mkdir
:e                     --&gt;  newfile / mkdir
(ctrl) + p             --&gt;  search for file
:%s/oldthing/newthing  --&gt;  replace
gg                     --&gt;  go to top
(shift) + g            --&gt;  go to bottom
ciw                    --&gt;  change inside of word
.                      --&gt;  repeat change
==                     --&gt;  align line correctly
= + (shift) + g        --&gt;  align everything below
(shift) + j            --&gt;  smash two lines together
(shift) + a            --&gt;  go to end of line
e                      --&gt;  go to the end of next word
w                      --&gt;  go to the beginning of next word
:sort                  --&gt;  sort the contents
:vs                    --&gt;  split the vim window

TMUX COMMANDS

tmux -2                    --&gt;  start tmux with darker color
(ctrl + a) + (shift + 5)   --&gt;  create two terminal windows vertical
(ctrl + a) + (shift + &#39;)   --&gt;  create two terminal windows horizontal 

&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;I hope to add to this ever growing knowledge of commands.  It is
easier to learn by practicing editing files without ever touching your mouse.  I
like to think of it as a style of the experts which is my goal to become.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Class Relationships</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/13/has-many-belongs-to/"/>
   <updated>2014-10-13T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/13/has-many-belongs-to</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Has Many and Belongs To&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a relationship we can define between classes in ruby which makes it
very easy to communicate between objects in rails.  If we decide to have an
application which has a Gallery model and an Image model ( &lt;em&gt;Note classes are
singular, controllers are plural&lt;/em&gt; ), we can relate the two simply by using the
code below:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;
class Gallery &lt; ActiveRecord::Base
  has_many :images
end

class Image &lt; ActiverRecord::Base
  belongs_to :gallery
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Pluralizing classes is important when using these connections with another
model.  It also helps to draw an ERD (Entity Relationship Diagram) to help
decide whether you need these connections.  It makes it easier to see a solution to a problem.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>I Shook Sinatra.rb's Hand</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/03/fall-into-october/"/>
   <updated>2014-10-03T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/10/03/fall-into-october</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;Week 2 Learning&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have made it through another week.&lt;/em&gt;  &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.sinatrarb.com/&quot;&gt;Sinatra&lt;/a&gt; is a DSL, domain specific
language, for creating web applications in Ruby.  It uses routes which are HTTP
methods paired with a URL matching pattern.  Each route has a block and I have
created many routes throughout the week.  It&#39;s very interesting and fun to build an
application and be able to view your work on a local server.  I find it
rewarding to finish a project in class at the end of the day.  It makes me focus
more during class and it helps me greatly later on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;I should log, about this blog, go for a jog, escape the fog&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I really, really, really, hope to figure out this blog setup and I might start
building it from scratch.  I can&#39;t figure out how to link pages to the older and
newer tags at the bottom of the page and it&#39;s frustrating.  I also recently
joined a gym so I can start jogging and work my way up to running again.  I miss
doing cardio and I think it would relieve a lot of stress.  It definitely has
been a tough week but I figure if I made it this far I can go farther for sure.&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>SQL and Final Project Status</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/09/29/sql-capstonepost/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-29T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/09/29/sql-capstonepost</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;SQL and Final Project Status 9/29/14&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I have a case of the Mondays.&lt;/em&gt;  I&#39;m not feeling too well, and I believe I
caught something from NYC&#39;s various subway systems.  It also means I will be
trying to get more rest for the next couple days.  I just learned some basic
Query language code which is not too complicated.  The biggest task will be to
use SQL effectively and without trouble later on.  I have a little bit of work
to do with my final project and I&#39;m not too sure I will be able to follow
through with my proposal.  It is hard to plan this far ahead considering we are
only through week 1.  Hopefully I will be able to figure out more within the
next few days.  Here are some SQL functions I have learned:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SELECT * FROM (table) WHERE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ORDER BY&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;LIKE and ILIKE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;OR, AND&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;IS NULL&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;...FROM (table) JOIN (another table) ON (primary = foreign keys)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;GROUP BY (label)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;INSERT INTO&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;UPDATE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;DELETE&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>Adam's Thoughts</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/09/26/introduction-adam/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/09/26/introduction-adam</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Dedicated to help and understanding.&lt;/em&gt;  The idea of this blog is to help me
understand the concepts I learn during the week.  Hopefully I will be able to
produce posts which provide help to others who have similar problems.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;h3&gt;Providing Information&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My webpage is located &lt;a href=&quot;http://a2k11.github.io&quot;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;.  I will also be working on
this site as time goes on.  It will get better over time, I guarantee it!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 
 <entry>
   <title>First Post</title>
   <link href="http://a2k11.github.io/2014/09/26/firstpost/"/>
   <updated>2014-09-26T00:00:00-04:00</updated>
   <id>http://a2k11.github.io/2014/09/26/firstpost</id>
   <content type="html">&lt;h3&gt;First Post 9/26/14&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;I&#39;m a part of this now.&lt;/em&gt;  My first week at the Ruby on Rails
&lt;a href=&quot;http://www.thisismetis.com&quot;&gt;Metis&lt;/a&gt; has been very cool so far.  I have met a lot
of new friends and have learned a lot about the programming language Ruby.  Here
is a list of what specifically I&#39;m working on with Ruby:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passing Blocks to Methods&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;def method(variable, &amp;amp;block)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;block.call&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;yield&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Symbols --&gt; :symbol&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Vim commands and becoming better at using it!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My typing skills&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;the methods .times, .each, and .map&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Arrays and Hashes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;


&lt;h3&gt;Other Thoughts / Reflection&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So it has been a week now and I&#39;m a little tired.  I definitely feel great about
the progress I&#39;ve made since Monday but I don&#39;t want to become content with just
being ok.  I&#39;m literally counting the nights until I move into the
&lt;a href=&quot;https://krash.io/&quot;&gt;Krash&lt;/a&gt; place I reserved through December.  Being only two
blocks away from class will be awesome and I will probably sleep better at
night.  I also will get to cook my meals again which is something I miss doing
since it helps me eat healthy foods.  My passion project at the end of this
course is still in the works.  I submitted my outline and I hope to have
feedback sooner than later.  I hope I get a chance to view some of the sites
while I&#39;m here in New York this weekend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Cheers!&lt;/p&gt;
</content>
 </entry>
 

</feed>
